today's video is going to be the luxury
cream comparison so we've got two of
possibly the most expensive creams
available here in Alberta we've got
vital green farms organic heavy cream 52
and Avalon Organic whipping cream
36 they have nothing in it
just milk cream
no stabilizers already added no
emulsifiers no preservatives they are
expensive
nine dollars for this
six and a half dollars for this six or
six and a half I can't remember
um
let's see if their ice cream is any
better than the Dairyland from the first
comparison video
[Music]
and we're doing the luxury cream right
now it's um I'm actually filming this
one second because the cream's about to
go off so in the pan here we've got the
same kind of mix but I'll give you the
numbers it's 420 grams of two percent
milk
150 grams of the vital greens 52
cream 100 grams of sugar 16 grams of
dextrose 31 grams of skim milk powder
and 20 grams of cocoa powder at 10 to 12
percent
so we're just going to get this all
mixed up and then I'm going to add in
the cream and get it in the fridge to
chill down
[Music]
the last luxury cream is Avalon I'll go
into more details about this in a bit
this one is 36 flat so in here we've got
330 grams of milk 205 what will be 205
grams of cream
once I
figure out the
Cut Thing
um
I will probably just eat that
and that's it let's uh
like last one we're going to get the
stirred up get this mixed together and
then we'll pop it in a container in the
fridge to chill for a few hours and then
we'll get this one churned up as well
and compare it to the vital greens cream
so let's see
[Music]
foreign
let's get it stirred
and then we'll get it churned
[Music]
first things to note is this one churned
much better much much better much faster
too this actually turned in
about 14 minutes so considerably faster
than
the other creams obviously this is a
luxury brand we'll talk about the price
and the difference later but
we're going to get this one loaded up
get it in the Free Zone just to chill
down properly and then we'll see how it
turned out
[Music]
the luxury cream has
an ice cream sticker so we don't get
confused
in overnight separation you can see
quite normal cocoa powder without any
kind of
without any additional ingredients we're
gonna
recombine everything a nice solid stir
for a minute or so
and then we'll get this in the ice cream
machine
[Music]
foreign
really hard very quickly
so this is in a much bigger container
than the other ones I will put a sticker
on it
I'm going to go for something small so
she won't get upset
cherries look
cherries on the Avalon cream it's gonna
go in the freezer and we'll compare the
two later
[Music]
luxury creams
so we have the one with the
little ice cream on
actually I think it's cupcake
this is the vital greens 52 percent
uh Alberta based company and this one
here with cherries on is the Avalon
cream
let's see which one's better
two very different results the vital
greens is a much lighter color much
smoother kind of mix the Avalon cream is
kind of
dark
unusual texture
I don't know
start with this one
very creamy as you'd expect
it's um
yeah we're
we're definitely getting somewhere
[Music]
smoother on the tongue much smaller Ice
Crystal formation
probably higher in solids somewhat
because of the cream makeup but
does dull the flavor
on the cocoa powder slightly
and at 12 percent
leaves a greasy film on the back of
speed you can feel it as well
this is likely because this is a
non-homogenized cream but we'll um I'll
get the tubs out of the fridge
in a minute and we'll just quickly talk
about them at the end
Avalon
okay it's just a surface underneath it's
absolutely fine
[Music]
water has a slightly greasy feel to it
not quite as creamy texture
and taste is the
vital greens but it's okay
slightly larger Ice Crystal formation in
this one as well none of these videos
these cream comparison videos have any
stabilizing at all because it's very
difficult to buy over here
without going for a commercial and I
just don't need that much
so I'm just going to wait until my
special ingredient stabilizer gets here
it's in our boxes still in Vancouver
I've messaged company hurry up and send
that stuff please
so
not as good as I was hoping
foreign
but certainly better
so pop these back in the freezer and I'm
going to get the creams out just so we
can go through them one last time
here we go these are the two that that
we've just compared
Okay so
luxury creams there's not a lot of
choice over here
it's not a choice back in England to be
fair
but
heavy cream
52 percent
Dairy Farmers of Canada
vital green Farms 250 milliliters
nearly nine dollars
nine Canadian dollars what is that about
seriously
Dairy Farmers of Canada and vital greens
nearly nine dollars the one liter
version of this is 22 in basically any
store I can find no one has it in stock
22 dollars for a a liter of cream
I can't even I can't even describe how
insane that actually is price wise
I don't get it
you're doing less work on this you're
doing less work as a Dairy Farmer to
produce this
get your charging
nearly nine dollars for 250 mil
Avalon
here we go this is this one
um
there's nothing in either of these it's
just it's just milk cream that that's it
but this one is 52 percent fat this one
I think is 36.
poor come on always
does it say on the front yeah 36.
um this one is a little bit cheaper I
think this one was six fifty six dollars
fifty Canadian for 200 and
50 maybe 250 mil
again six dollars it's insane
for something this small cream with a
reasonable amount of fat on yes this I
think is organic
yeah it is so you know that seems to
give people the excuse to charge twice
as much as they should that will go for
this one as well yes but come on
really
I don't think at the moment it's worth
buying these because it just costs too
much money and no one in the right mind
is going to pay
that much money for this
nine dollars six and a half dollars for
for some cream so we need to find
a better option I was going to do this
video the luxury cream one last but as
these were running out and I had two of
each I thought I didn't do this second
so the last video is going to be
all right these two I think are going to
be I hope are going to be our Saving
Grace they're off the shelf Safeway
sobies not really expensive easy to get
hold of and they're not full of crap so
let's see how the last pair of creams
get on in our Canadian cream conundrum
Series so thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe I'll
see you next time
[Music]
thank you